

Oakville, ON, Canada

□(+1) 2892596430 | ☑ liuchew@shernet.sheridancollege.ca | # palmswill.github.io/react-resume2021/ | ☑ palmswill | 匝 williamliucs

## **Summary**

2+ years React-based web developer with experiences in business management and sales campaigns on e-Commerce platforms with front-end knowledge such as React library, HTML5, CSS3 and back-end knowledge such as NodeJs, Express REST API, Amazon S3, Firebase and Google API. Currently studying at Sheridan College and looking for an internship focusing on modern web development.

## Professional Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### **Tribute Window Coverings**

Mississauga, Canada

SMART HOME PRODUCT SUPPORT MANAGEMENT

Nov. 2019 - Present

- Provided product support for mechanical products, created online instruction videos and product manual receiving over 80 % positive feedback and product sales was observed to increase by more than 10% in the same period.
- Technical supported the company, included computer set up, software problems encountered etc. Reduced the IT support cost per month by more than 20 %.

### Taiwan Intelligence Service Corps,

Taichung, S.Taiwan (Remote)

ASSOCIATE ARCHITECTURE AND SYSTEM DESIGNER (CONTRACT)

April 2019 - April 2021

- Improved performance by redesigning database and created and modify user interface.
- · Created and modify user interface ,use cases and user flow design by communicating with the clients
- · Created detailed user manuals and release including issues and bug tracking

### **Tribute Window Coverings**

Mississauga, Canada

SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGEMENT

November 2017- November 2019

- Generated daily sales and inventory report, estimated the needed purchase based on report status. Accurately predicted sales trend preventing over or shortage of stock reducing department back-order rate by 20% in 2018 compared to previous years.
- · In charge of communication between vendors. Negotiated the price and brought down the cost of products for more than 10%.

## Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6,HTML5,CSS3,Java

Front End Libraries & Tools: ReactJ(Router, Redux Toolkit, Context API etc), Semantic UI, Bootstrap

Back Ends: NodeJs, Amazon S3, Google API, Firebase, Auth0

**Others:** Data analysis,Tech Support,Database Design, Microsoft Office,ERP,Quickbook

# **Projects**

### **TWC E-Commerce Project (In Progress)**

HTTPS://E-WEBSITE-TCC.HEROKUAPP.COM/

July. 2021 - Present

- An E-Commerce website that is built for online ordering for Tribute Window Coverings.
- A React front end website cooperating with ERP database, Amazon S3 image cloud and auth0 authentication.

#### **Spacetagram**

HTTP://NASAPOD2021.HEROKUAPP.COM/

September,2021

- A responsive NASA picture of the day liker.
- Built with React front-end, Semantic UI & NASA POD API.

### The Shoppies

HTTPS://MOVIECHALLENGE2021.HEROKUAPP.COM/

April,2021

- A shareable movie nominator website.
- Built with React front end, Semantic UI and Movie IMDB API.

# **Education**

### **Sheridan College**

Oakville, Canada

Sep. 2020 - April. 2023

Software Development & Network Engineering (GPA:3.6/4)

• Relevant Courses: Enterprise Java, Web Programming, Interactive User Design, UX/UI Design

SEPTEMBER 21, 2021 WILLIAM LIU · RÉSUMÉ